Cd. de México Mobile: +52 55 5506 4643 oscar.ahuatl@amail.com

Oscar Alejandro Mejia Ahuatl

Background:

Accomplished Manager, Architect and Analyst with over 20 years of experience in IT operations. Extensive experience in banking electronic transactions, IT projects, development projects, IT operation, innovation and strategic planning.

Skills & Techniques: team Leadership, analytical thinking, communication, Negotiation. self learning, TOGAF, UML,, BA skills, cloud computing, programming knowledge, testing, SCRUM cloud computing, RestFul API, ETL, development, Project manager and Scrum Master Skills, design

Objective:

Use my technical and management skills for achieving objectives. I look to implement innovative ideas and be creativity for accomplishing projects.

Experience:

2015 – Present	Strategic Impact Solutions IT Manager, IT Architect, BSA, Tech Product Owner	2015 - Present
2003 – 2015	IT Architect	2010 - 2015 2005 - 2010 2003 - 2005
2000 – 2003	Network & Systems consulting group Project leader Developer & Analyst	2000 - 2003 2000 - 2000
1999 - 2000	Axxis IT Developer & Analyst	1999 – 2000

Education:

- Master degree in Information technology management ,Instituto Telmex, (2012-2014)
- **Bachelor of System Engineer**, United University, (1996-2000)
- AWS Solution Architect, (2017)
- Multiple courses of Cloud, RestAPI (2017-2020)
- **Scrum Master**, certificated (2016)
- TOGAF Enterprise Architecture, certificated (2013)
- Finance concepts, ITAM University (2011)
- ITIL Fundamentals V3.0, (2010)
- Sun certified programmer, SCJP. (2006)
- Multiple programming courses: NodeJs, Python, ETL (2016-2021)
- Multiple courses of Unix (2002 to 2005)
- Multiple courses about team work and soft skills (2016-2021)

Languages:

Complete knowledge of the English language and Spanish native speaker

Achievements, Projects & Implementations

Strategic Impact Solutions, IT-Services Manager

I joined Stratis to start a new area for the company: IT-Services, my job started in Chicago USA with the service of implementation for Accertify, an American Express Company. Nowadays we have up to 10 services, 7 clients and 40 members in the area.

Our services: Implementation, support, Testing, Business analysis, presales, Technical writing, project management, and management of Infrastructure as a Service

Currently our main focus is in the management of full cycle development projects from requirement definitions to support, working mainly as Enterprise Architect and development coordinator

Mayor Achievements:

- 1.44 M USD annual revenue
- Integration of cloud services with AWS in different client's platforms and systems
- Increase of portfolio solutions from 1 to up 10
- Increase of our clients from 1 to 7
- IT Architectural design for 3 Android/IoS apps with cloud computing backEnd

Promoción y operación SA de CV (PROSA)

PROSA's PMO does not only focus in the management of projects instead the PMO is focused on the design of technological solutions and coordination of projects, Three main group are part of the team: Technological Architects, system designers and project managers, I was responsible for managing and supervising up to 20 engineers.

Our goal was the improvements to existing systems, the technological design of new products and services and the definition of information and operational workflows.

Our main client was the ABM (Mexico's Bank association), which means we work to design and deliver countrywide projects, involving up to 20 banks and brands like MasterCard & Visa

Mayor Achievements:

- Implementation of surcharge in the ATM's Network knows as RED in six months, this includes the design of the national standard and the coordination of 25 banks
- Implementation of JCB as issuer in ATMs in eight months. JCB is one of the main issuers of credit cards in Japan; they want that their card could be accepted in Mexican ATM's network without using the MasterCard network.
- Enterprise Architecture implementation in PROSA. Looking for give more value to our customers, PROSA's PMO is adopting EA principles, so their solution become more than a technological product; we look for give a business scope.

Freelance Systems designer and developer

For a couple of months my main activities were designed and develop of web applications with Java J2EE and ASP technology, using SQL Server and Access database Managers.

Mayor Achievements:

Design, coding and implementation of a web system for the Instituto Mexicano del Seguro Social (IMSS) where doctors who travel around the country captures their activities for monitoring purposes.

Network & Systems Consulting Group

Position: Systems analyst, Developer, and Network support

Main Activities:

- 2 Tiers applications developments using SQL Server and Sybase databases
- Analysis, design and development of Java, Visual Basic application
- Design and Installation of WAN networks
- LAN networks configuration
- Troubleshooting network connectivity issues.

Mayor Achievements:

- Install and Configure Company's iplanet WebServer
- Install and Configure Company's File Server in Windows 2000
- Design and Install WAN networks for Pemex

Axxis Consulting

Main Activities:

- Develop in 2 Tiers applications with SQL Server and Sybase databases
- Analysis, design and development of Visual Basic applications.

Mayor Achievements:

Successful implementation of Danone's inventory system around the country.